Guide to the Walter De la Mare Papers, 1912-1984
Department of Special Collections
Walter De la Mare Papers,
1912-1984
Special Collections M0589
De la Mare, Walter, 1873-1956.
4 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Dorothy L. Hatch, 1991 and 1993.
Scope and Content
Includes letters, manuscripts, muscical scores, and printed ephemera collected by Dorothy Hatch. Major correspondents include John Black, Richard Church, Leonard Clark, Graham Greene, Dorothy Hatch, Edward Marsh, Barbara Morison, Christopher Morley, Lady Ottoline Morrell, F. C. Owlett, Herman Peschmann, and Elizabeth Myers Powys.
Includes poetry and letters by Edward Marsh. Clippings of drama and book reviews.
Reprints about De la Mare.
Access Terms
Black, John, 1922-; Church, Richard, 1893-; Clark, Leonard.; Greene, Graham, 1904-; Marsh, Edward.; Morison, Barbara.; Morley, Chrisotpher, 1890-1957.; Morrell, Ottoline Violet Anne Cavendish-Bentinck, Lady, 1873-1938.; Owlett, F. C.; Peschmann, Herman.; Powys, Elizabeth Myers.; English literature--20th century.; Hatch, Dorothy L. Collector.
Container List
- Correspondence
  - 24 postcards, WDLM to Lady Ottoline Morrell, 1927-1931;some n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 14 letters, WDLM to Elizabeth Myers Powys, 1944,including 1 autograph poem (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 13 letters, WDLM to Elizabeth Myers Powys, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2 letters, WDLM to Littleton Powys, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 17 letters, WDLM to Elizabeth Myers Powys, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1 telegram, WDLM to Elizabeth Myers Powys, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 3 letters, WDLM to Littleton Powys, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to John Black, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to John Black, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to John Black, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2 TLS, WDLM to Richard Church, 1940,including ALS from Church to Hudson (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2 ALS, WDLM to Laurence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Conal O'Riordan, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 5 TLS, WDLM to Miss English, 1935-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2 TLS, WDLM to Dr. Hurst (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Christopher Morley ( 1890-1957,editor and writer at Doubleday, Page (1913-17)and Ladies Home Journal (1917-18)), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 4 ALS, WDLM to F.C. Owlett, 1940-53 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 12 TLS, WDLM to F.C. Owlett, 1940-53 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1 postcard, signed, WDLM to F.C. Owlett, 1940-53 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1 autograph poem, WDLM to F.C. Owlett, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 7 TLS, WDLM to Hermann Peschmann, 1933-46 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 2 ALS, WDLM to Hermann Peschmann, 1941-46 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 3 autograph correspondence cards, WDLM to Hermann Peschmann, 1 n.d., 1948, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1 autograph postcard, WDLM to Peschmann, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 3 ALS, 1 TLS, WDLM to Frederick B. Eddy, 1922-24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 10 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 envelope [1953]WDLM to Mrs. Gerald Bishop, 1919-25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 5 ALS, 3 TLS, WDLM to Gerald Bishop, [1919]-1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Lescelles Abercrombie, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 4 ALS, 7 TLS, 4 envelopes, WDLM to Catherine Abercrombie, 1940-53 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 7 ALS, WDLM to Mrs. Bromley, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 2 Christmas cards, signed, WDLM to Edward and Barbara Morison, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1 autograph correspondence card, WDLM to Barbara Morison, with envelope, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 3 envelopes, WDLM to Barbara Morison, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 7 ALS, 1 ALS with envelope, 3 TLS, 2 TLS with envelope, WDLM to Barbara Morison, 1946-56 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 3 TLS, WDLM to Sir Sidney Roberts, 1931-34 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 3 ALS, WDLM to Mr. Tadler, [1910] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2 autograph poems, The Monkey and the Dolphin and The Oracle and the Impious Man, by Edward Marsh, after LaFontaine (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1 ALS, with envelope, Edward Marsh to Frank Pleadwell, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1 newspaper clipping from Pretoria, South Africa, on Marsh's bequest of 400 paintings to Commonwealth museums (Box 1, Folder 11)
    both items previously enclosed in a copy of Marsh's autobiography
  - 1 TMs, 6pp., WDLM's recollections of Edward Marsh, intended for Eddie Marsh: Sketches for a Composite Literary Portrait, ed. Hassall and Marlieus [?] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 3 postcards from Leonard Clark (b. 1905, friend and protege of WDLM) to Sir Sidney Cockerell, 1958-9 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1 TLS from Leonard Clark to Mary MacArthur, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 3 TLS, 1 ALS from Leonard Clark to John Smith [?], 1962-4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1 ALS, Leonard Clark to William, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 2 sets of galley proofs, 1 autograph Ms and 1 typed Ms, both signed, for Six Poems for Children (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1 typed Ms poem Full Circle, with signed notes to John Smith (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1 typed Ms Ideas in Poetry (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 3 ALS, Leonard Clark to H. Simpson, 1953-56,re: election to Royal Literary Society (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 3 ALS, Mary Winter Were [pseudonym; i.e., Mary E.J. Hughes] to Henry Simpson, 1950.re: election to RLS (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1 typed p. reviews (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1 ALS, Richard Church to John Smith (ed. Poetry Review), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 3p. typed Ms, signed R Church, Shakespeare Sonnet Competition (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 9 ALS, 18 TLS, 7 A/TLS, WDLM to Revd. J.A. Bouquet (1875-1971),a contemporary of WDLM's at St. Paul's Choir School, 1939-53,with notes by Bouquet's son (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 2 ALS, WDLM to Mrs. Fletcher, 1919, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Dear Madam, 1919.re: anthology (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to C.K. Ogden (ed. Cambridge Magazine), 1920[?],with transcription (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Dear Sir, 1920,with transcription. re: setting poem to music (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Mr. Walker, 1921,with transcription (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Dear Madam, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to J.A. Craig, 1922.re: use of portrait photograph (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 2 TLS, WDLM to Mr. Farjeon, 1923.re: setting The Truant to music (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Mr. Atkinson, 1923.re: reading at club (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Mr. Barrett, 1923. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Mr. Brown, 1925.re: anthology (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Dear Brereton, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Dear Bayliss, with transciption (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Miss Muster, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to James Wells (U.S. publisher), 1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, Owen Mase to WDLM, 1929.re: broadcast of musical setting of England (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Mr. Telfer, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 2 TLS, WDLM to Franklin Ludington, with envelopes, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1 TL, Franklin Ludington to WDLM, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 2 autograph poems, WDLM to J.N. Hart (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1 ALS, Lord Dunsany to Dorothy Una Ratcliffe, with envelope, 1935;and ALS reply (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1 autograph Ms, To my sister April 20th, with cartoons [not in WDLM's hand] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Mr. Roberts, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Peter Windsor (U.S. poet), with envelope, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Graham Greene, 1945.re: Greene's approval of WDLM's Burning Glass, and WDLM's praise for Power and Glory (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1 autograph correspondence card to Graham Greene, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1 ALS, WDLM to Sheila, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 6 TLS, 1 ALS, WDLM to Fred Bason (author and bookseller), with envelopes, 1950-55 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Rebecca Mixner, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1 TLS, WDLM to Eleanor Farjeon, with envelope, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1 ALS, Richard De La Mare to Ryan [ed. London Times?], 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1 TLS, Richard De La Mare to Richard Church, 1969.re: edition of Complete Poems of WDLM (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Postcard of Walter de la Mare to Dorothy Hatch. October 7, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ian Macdonald to Dorothy Hatch. July 19, 1976.Also an order form with a note from Macdonald to Hatch on the back. May 24, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Letter from R. L. Megroz to Kyle. August 23, 1941.Letter from R. L. Megroz to Kyle, August 23, 1941. (Box 3)
  - The Flower. n.d. (Box 3)
  - Letter from David Howland to Dorothy Hatch. January 19, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from Dorothy Hatch to David Howland. January 21, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Letter from David Howland to Dorothy Hatch. January 30, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Letter from David Howland to Dorothy Hatch. February 11, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Letter from David Howland to Dorothy Hatch. April 26, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Letter from David Howland to Dorothy Hatch. May 3, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Letter from David Howland to Dorothy Hatch. May 20, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Letter from David Howland to Dorothy Hatch. June 9, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Letter from David Howland to Dorothy Hatch. August 20, 1976. (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from Dorothy Hatch to the Howlands. August 29, 1976., 2 copies. (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from de la Mare to Howland. April 24, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from de la Mare to Howland. June 6, 1924. (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from de la Mare to Howland. September 4, 1924. (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from de la Mare to Howland. September 18, 1924. (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from de la Mare to Virgina. July 24, 1937. (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from de la Mare to Virginia. November 2, 1937. (Box 3)
  - Xerox of letter from Thomas M. Whitehead to Dorothy Hatch. January 14, 1988.In same box are xeroxes of 10 pgs. of background notes about de la Mare and Elizabeth Meyers, written by Dorothy Hatch, followed by a xeroxed list of the letters, and then by xeroxes of the transcribed letters. (Box 3)
  - Dame Hickory. n.d.With original drawing, unsigned. Pencil, ink and wash.
- Manuscript Poems by WDLM
  - Lady Godiva, typed, publ. New Statesman, 8 Sept 1917 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Blind Boy, autograph, dated 7 March 1914 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Blind!, autograph (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Night, typed, with transcription. Dated 1913. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - In the woods..., with transcription. 1917[?] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sam's Three Wishes, autograph, inscribed to old Jimblepaggles from D[ad?] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Coldharbour Ballad, typed, with autograph interleaf, 1911.addressed to Naomi G. Royde-Smith (1880?-1964),literary editor for Saturday Westminster Gazette (1912-22) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 11 early typed Ms, 13pp., from The Listener (1912)and Peacock Pie (1913) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Chorister Publications
  - 1 Vol. Chorister's Journal, 1889-1890(reprint). Journal of St. Paul's Choir School, founded by WDLM (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1 Vol. Chorister's Magazine. Dec. 1976,with explanatory letter (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Manuscripts (musical scores)
  - Autumn. 1933. (Box 2)
  - The Horseman. n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Cupboard. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Music. 1932. (Box 2)
  - Silver. 1980. (Box 2)
  - Silver. n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Song of the Mad Prince. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Silver. March, 1935. (Box 2)
  - Lines from Peacock Pie. n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Witch. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Silver. 1931. (Box 2)
  - Epitaph. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Echoes. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Nod: The Old Shepherd. 1930 (Box 2)
  - Old Shellover and Moon Song. 1924. (Box 2)
  - Silver. 1936. (Box 2)
  - Three Songs from Peacock Pie. n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Three Cherry Trees. n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Cupboard. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Tired Tim. n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Barber's. n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Song of the Secret. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Silver. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Silver. n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Song of the Shadows. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Music. n.d. (Box 2)
  - As I Sat Musing. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mistletoe. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Where? n.d. (Box 2)
  - Where? n.d. (Box 2)
  - Down Adown Derry. Fragment. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Verdict for Mary: A Play in Three Parts. By Naomi Royde-Smith. n.d. (Box 3)
  - Return from Abroad: A Play in Three Acts. By Ernest Milton. n.d. (Box 3)
  - David: A Comedy in Three Acts. By N. G. Royde-Smith. Act 1. n.d. (Box 3)
  - David: A Comedy in Three Acts. By N. G. Royde-Smith. Act 2. n.d. (Box 3)
  - David: A Comedy in Three Acts. By N. G. Royde-Smith. Act 3. n.d. (Box 3)
- SCORES
  (see also Box 10 for Music Scores)
  - Wanderers - Unaccompanied song. 1924., 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - Three Choral Songs. 1968., 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - England. 1928. (Box 4)
  - Hide and seek. 1929., 5 copies. (Box 4)
  - The Huntsman. 1933., 3 copies. (Box 4)
  - Dream Song. 1935. (Box 4)
  - The Three Cherry trees. 1924., 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - The Sleeping Beauty. 1925., 4 copies. (Box 4)
  - Silver. In Sing It and Ring It. 1966. (Box 4)
  - The Silver Penny. 1966., 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - Nicholas Nye. 1962. (Box 4)
  - The Ship of Rio. 1958. (Box 4)
  - Andy Battle. 1933. (Box 4)
  - Echoes. 1932., 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - Hide and Seek. 1925. (Box 4)
  - Mistletoe. 1925. (Box 4)
  - Shellover. 1925. (Box 4)
  - The Trees of England. 1933., 3 copies. (Box 4)
  - The Ship of Rio. n.d. (Box 4)
  - The Quartet. n.d. (Box 4)
  - The Scarecrow. 1934. (Box 4)
  - The Snow. 1923. (Box 4)
  - Nine and Ninety Monkeys. 1938., 3 copies. (Box 4)
  - The Sunken Garden. 1926. (Box 4)
  - The Song of the Soldiers. 1933. (Box 4)
  - The Fly. 1938., 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - A Little Sound. 1935., 3 copies. (Box 4)
  - Down-Adown-Derry. 1925.4 copies vocal. 2 copies each of 1st violin, 2nd violin, viola, cello, pianoforte and flute. (Box 4)
  - Once and There Was a Young Sailor. 1927., 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - Mistletoe. 1925., 4 copies. (Box 4)
  - Tit for Tat: Five settings from boyhood of poems by Walter de la Mare. Benjamin Britten. 1969. (Box 4)
  - Index to The Chapbook, numbers one to twelve (July, 1919 - June, 1920).In same holder, Full Moon. (Set to music.) The Monthly Chapbook. No. 18, December, 1920.In same holder, Nod, Melmillo, and Arabia. (All set to music.) The Monthly Chapbook. No. 6, vol. 1. December, 1919. (Box 4)
  - Misc. Scores (in box 4) (Box 4)
  - Nursery Rhymes of London Town. Book 2. Eleanor Farjeon. 1921. (Box 4)
  - Come! Christmas Come! 1929. (Box 4)
  - Songs from Punch. Eleanor Farjeon. n.d. (Box 4)
- OTHER, de la Mare
  - A Local Habitation and a Name. The Imprint of the Stanford Libraries Associates. October, 1979.By Dorothy Hatch. (Box 5)
  - Here Lies... and The Dead Jay. In Poetry, February, 1939. (Box 5)
  - Desert Islands. The Golden Book Magazine. October, 1930. (Box 5)
  - Meeting Thomas Hardy. The Listener. April, 1955. (Box 5)
  - Bad Company. The Listener. April, 1954. (Box 5)
  - Chardin. 1948. (Box 5)
  - Chardin. 1950. (Box 5)
  - Another Washington. In The Listener. August, 1950., 2 copies. (Box 5)
  - The Minstrel. In The Listener. April, 1956. (Box 5)
  - Christmas Eve. In Nash's - Pall Mall. December, 1925. (Box 5)
  - Beyond. In The Listener. August, 1950. (Box 5)
  - The Chinese Pot. In The Listener. April, 1953. (Box 5)
  - Ulladore. In The Listener. July, 1952. (Box 5)
  - The Burnt Letter. In The Listener. March, 1950. (Box 5)
  - Solitude. In The Listener. May, 1950. (Box 5)
  - Strangers and Pilgrims. Nash's - Pall Mall. April, 1936. (Box 5)
  - Sturge Moore's Poems. The Bookman. June, 1914. (Box 5)
  - The Green Room: A Bookshop Story. The Bookman's Journal. September, 1925. (Box 5)
  - In the Dock. In Broom. November, 1921. (Box 5)
  - Mr. Belloc's Essays The Bookman. April, 1908. (Box 5)
  - Walter de la Mare. By Kenneth Hopkins. 1957. (Box 5)
  - Walter de la Mare: A Tribute. By Leonard Clark and Edmund Blunden. 1974. (Box 5)
  - Walter de la Mare, Poet and Writer of Huguenot Extraction. In Proceedings of the the Huguenot Society of London. Vol. 20, No. 4. 1963 for 1962. (Box 5)
  - Walter de la Mare. By Kenneth Hopkins. 1969., (05) (Box 5)
- Oversized Scores
  - Nod. 1920. (Box 6)
  - Three Poems from Peacock Pie Set to Music by Walter M. Clement. 1920. (Box 6)
  - The Beautiful Lady. Fragment. 1912. (Box 6)
- Albums of Newspaper Cuttings
  - Album of newspaper cuttings. The Property of Ernest Milton inscribed on inside of front cover. Primarily drama reviews. (Box 7)
  - Album of newspaper cuttings. Primarily drama reviews. (Box 7)
  - Album of newspaper cuttings. Primarily book reviews. (Box 7)
  - Album of newspaper cuttings. Primarily play reviews. (Box 7)
  - Album of newspaper cuttings. Primarily book reviews. (Box 8)
- More De La Mare Ephemera
  - Centenary Recitals (birthday of Walter de la Mare). Presented by the Schubert Society of Great Britian. June 15 [1973]. (Box 8)
  - The Journal of the National Book League: Walter de la Mare. April-May, 1956. (Box 8)
  - The English Association Presidential Address: Walter de la Mare. Lord David Cecil. July, 1973. (Box 8)
  - Crossings. Wakefield Girls' High School Program. n.d. (Box 8)
  - To Lucy. Unbound printer's proof. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Memoirs of a Midget. Book review. Book of the Month Club News. (An Outstanding Older Book). June, 1928. (Box 8)
  - Royde-Smith, Naomi Gwaldys. Twentieth Century Authors. 1942.p. 1208. Note De La Mare's beloved `NG'. Her `Binns'. (Box 8)
  - Walter de la Mare. W. H. Auden. Newspaper clipping. No paper name. n.d.In the same holder, An Appreciation of the Lyric Verse of Walter de la Mare. W. H. Auden. Newspaper clipping. No paper name. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Review of The Complete Poems of Walter de la Mare. Naomi Lewis. The New York Times Book Review. July 5, 1970.p. 4, 15. (Box 8)
  - Walter de la Mare is Dead; British Poet, Author, was 83. Obituary from the New York Herald Tribune. June 23, 1956.In same holder, announcement of An Exhibition at the National Book League to Mark his Eighty-Third Birthday: Mr. Walter de la Mare, O.D. Photograph. The Illustrated London News. May 28, 1956. (Box 8)
  - Newspaper photograph of Walter de la Mare. n.d.In same holder, magazine photograph of Walter de la Mare. n.d.In same holder, newspaper review of Ding-Dong Bell. n.d.In same holder, pamphlet Walter de la Mare and a List of His Poetry... n.d. (Box 8)
  - Study in Blond: Mrs. Richard de la Mare and Her Children. Vogue Magazine. January 15, 1966.p. 108-9. In same holder, The Beautiful People in Caftans. With a photograph of Mrs. Richard de la Mare. [ Vogue? n.d.] (Box 8)
  - The Watching Eye. Newspaper clipping. n.d.In same holder, The Ruined Abbey. Newspaper clipping. n.d.In same holder, C. Armnstrong Gibbs recalls the first performance of `Crossings'. Radio Times. December 15, 1950.p. 5. In same holder, The Friend of Life, Mr. de la Mare's New Poems. The Times Literary Supplement. November 17, 1945. (Box 8)
  - Walter de la Mare obituary. n.d.In same holder, Walter de la Mare obituary. The Times. June 23, 1956.In same holder, xerox of Walter de la Mare, Poet, Dead; Author of Stories for Children. The New York Times. June 23, 1956.In same holder, Mr. de la Mare's Anthology. Review of Behold, This Dreamer. n.d.In same holder, newspaper clipping Mr. Walter de la Mare. T. Cannon Brookes. 1956.In same holder, newspaper clipping Angel of Words. Kenneth Young. [1956]., 2 copies. (Box 8)
  - Walter de la Mare's Poetry. Wen Yuan-ning. In T'ien Hsia Monthly. Reprint frim April Issue, 1936. (Box 8)
  - Walter de la Mare: An Exhibition of Books, Letters, Manuscripts. March 3 - April 5, 1969.Rare Book Department, Temple University Libraries, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Inside catalog, letter from Thomas Whitehead, Rare Book and Manuscript Curator, to Dorothy Hatch, certifying receipt of loan items for the de la Mare exhibition. Also, a news release of the exhibition. (Box 8)
  - The Burial of Walter de la Mare. St. Paul's Cathedral. June 28, 1956.Two slides of the de la Mare memorial plaque in St. Paul's Cathedral. Photographed September, 1973.Three photographs of de la Mare memorial plaque and area just off St. Faith Chapel in the crypt of St. Paul's Cathedral. Photographed September, 1973.One photograph of de la Mare memorial plaque in St. Paul's Cathedral. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Haunted. Linden Broadsheet No. 4. Christmas, 1939.2 proof copies, different states, one hand tinted. Artist and engraver: Honor Frost. (Box 8)
  - Two Poems. ( The Truth of Things and Pride.) The Dropmore Poems. - No. 4. Signed by Walter de la Mare. No. 36 of 100. July, 1946. (Box 8)
  - The Old Men. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Photograph of Walter de la Mare. By Mark Gerson. n.d.In same holder, review of Ding-Dong Bell. n.d. In same holder, review of Epitaphs, by W. H. Beable. (Box 8)
  - Review of The Complete Poems of Walter de la Mare. Naomi Lewis. New York Times Book Review. July 5, 1970.p.4. (Box 8)
  - Bibliography of books about de la Mare, along with an announcement of an annotated bibliography of twientieth century literature. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Flyer for Come Hither. n.d.In same holder, ad for books by de la Mare. (Box 8)
  - Xerox of Ricardus Librorum Faber. Berthold Wolpe. The Book Collector. p. 345-8. In same holder, audio tape of nine epitaphs from de la Mare's Ding-Dong Bell. Taped from KUSC, September 1986. (Box 8)
  - Xerox of entry on de la Mare from Critical Survey of Poetry. ed. Frank Magill. 1982.p. 773-81. (Box 8)
  - Xerox of an auction catalog of de la Mare autograph letters and literary manuscripts. July 13, 1966.[Sotheby's, London.] Also, a cover letter from Sotheby's to Mrs. M. Cohn. July 4, 1972. (Box 8)
  - Xerox of Walter de la Mare's Stories for Children. Jane E. Gardner. The Private Library. Third series, vol. 1:3. Autumn,1978.p. 100-18. (Box 8)
  - Cover for The Three Mulla-Mulgars. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Horn Book Calendar for 1951, with quotations from Walter de la Mare. (Box 8)
  - Photograph of Walter de la Mare. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Photograph of Walter de la Mare. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Certified copy of Walter de la Mare's entry of birth. (Box 8)
  - Certified copy of Walter de la Mare's entry of death. (Box 8)
  - Drawing of de la Mare by Nicolas Bentley. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Some Thoughts on Reading. Address by de la Mare at Bembridge School, July 6, 1923.No. 192 of 350. (Box 8)
  - Books for Children. The Literary Review. November 10, 1923.Newspaper clipping in album. (Box 8)
  - Review of Mulla-Mulgars. n.d.In same holder, invitation to an exhibition of Dorothy Lathrop's drawings. New Haven. In same holder, newspaper clipping of a drawing by Dorothy Lathrop. n.d. (Box 8)
  - New de la Mare Stories. R. L. Megroz. The Bookman. October, 1930. (Box 8)
  - The Personality of Walter de la Mare. V. Sackville-West. The Listener. April 30, 1953. (Box 8)
  - Review of Peacock Pie. Edward Thomas. The Bookman. September, 1913. (Box 8)
  - Modern First Editions. Catalogue No. 115. De la Mare, p. 12-3. Spring, 1959. (Box 8)
  - Off the Ground and The Horseman. (Primary Division school assignment.) n.d. (Box 8)
  - Crossword puzzle, 1 down is de la Mare's name. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Ad for de la Mare autograph letter, inserted in a book by Rupert Brooke. n.d. (Box 8)
  - Program for the Henry Elias Howland Memorial Prize. Note on cover states 1st award to Rupert Brooke was accepted by W. J. de la Mare as per Brooke's will. (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous
  - Much Hadham Hall. Sold by direction of Richard de la Mare, Esq. Sotheby's auction catalogue, September 30 and October 1, 1980. (Box 9)
  - The Bookman. January, 1913. (Box 9)
  - The Monthly Chapbook. No. 3, vol. 1. September, 1919. (Box 9)
  - Festival of Poetry, 1963.Souvenir Programme. (Box 9)
  - Xerox of entry on Elizabeth Myers. Catholic Authors. ed. Matthew Hoehn. v. 2. p. 378-9. (Box 9)
  - Photograph A Memory of Ellen Terry. Clipping from a magazine., 2 copies. (Box 9)
  - Photograph. Portrait from the Naomi Royde-Smith Collection. n.d. (Box 9)